<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Help>
  <Command Name="Chat_Protocol" />
  <Syntax>a Connection</Syntax>
  <Description>
Caller: 

Once a connection is made the caller sends a connection string which looks like: "CHAT:&lt;chat name&gt;\n&lt;ip address&gt;&lt;port&gt;".
The sprintf syntax is: "CHAT:%s\n%s%-5u". The port must be 5 characters, padded on the right side with spaces. Once this
string has been sent it waits for a response from the other side. If a "NO" is received the call is cancelled. If the call
was accepted the string "YES:&lt;chat name&gt;\n" is received. 

Receiver: 

When a socket call is detected it accepts the socket then waits for the "CHAT:" string to be send from the caller. If the
receiver wishes to deny the call, the string "NO" needs to be sent back to the caller. To accept the call, the string
"YES:&lt;chat name&gt;\n" is sent back.

Chat Data Blocks

A chat data block looks like this: &lt;COMMAND BYTE&gt;&lt;data&gt;&lt;END OF COMMAND&gt;. All data dealing with needs to follow this format
with a couple exceptions. The connection process doesn't use the data blocks and the file transfer blocks are a fixed size
and don't need the &lt;END OF COMMAND&gt; byte.

List of the &lt;COMMAND BYTE&gt; values

CHAT_NAME_CHANGE                      1
CHAT_REQUEST_CONNECTIONS              2
CHAT_CONNECTION_LIST                  3
CHAT_TEXT_EVERYBODY                   4
CHAT_TEXT_PERSONAL                    5
CHAT_TEXT_GROUP                       6
CHAT_MESSAGE                          7
CHAT_DO_NOT_DISTURB                   8

CHAT_VERSION                         19
CHAT_FILE_START                      20
CHAT_FILE_DENY                       21
CHAT_FILE_BLOCK_REQUEST              22
CHAT_FILE_BLOCK                      23
CHAT_FILE_END                        24
CHAT_FILE_CANCEL                     25
CHAT_PING_REQUEST                    26
CHAT_PING_RESPONSE                   27
CHAT_PEEK_CONNECTIONS                28
CHAT_PEEK_LIST                       29
CHAT_SNOOP_START                     30
CHAT_SNOOP_DATA                      31

CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND                 255

&lt;CHAT_NAME_CHANGE&gt;&lt;new name&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

When a user changes their chat name the new name needs to be broadcast to all of their connections.

&lt;CHAT_REQUEST_CONNECTIONS&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

Requests connections from another connection asking to see all the people that person has marked as public, then try to
connect to all of those yourself.

&lt;CHAT_CONNECTION_LIST&gt;&lt;address&gt;,&lt;port&gt;,&lt;address&gt;,&lt;port&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

The receiver needs to put all the IPs and port numbers of the public connections in a comma delimited string and send them
back as a connection list.

&lt;CHAT_TEXT_EVERYBODY&gt;&lt;text to send&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

Used to send some chat text to everybody. All the text you want to be displayed needs to be generated on the sender's side,
including the line feeds and the "&lt;chat name&gt; chats to everybody" string. 

Receiver: 

If the chat connection isn't being ignored, you simply print the string. If you have any connections marked as being served
you need to echo this string to those connections. Or if this is coming from a connection being served, you need to echo to
all your other connections. This allows people who cannot connect directly to each other to connect with a 3rd person who
*can* connect to both and be a server for them.

&lt;CHAT_TEXT_PERSONAL&gt;&lt;text to send&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

This works the same way as CHAT_TEXT_EVERYBODY as far as what you need to send. The text should obviously be changed so the
person receiving knows this was a personal chat and not broadcast to everybody. 

Receiver: 

Just print the string that comes in if you aren't ignoring this connection.

&lt;CHAT_TEXT_GROUP&gt;&lt;group&gt;&lt;text to send&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

Used when you send text to a specific group of connections. Works basically the same as the other text commands. The group
name is a 15 character string. It *must* be 15 characters long and pad it on the right with spaces to fill it out. 

Receiver: 

Just print the string that comes in if you aren't ignoring this connection.

&lt;CHAT_MESSAGE&gt;&lt;message&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

This is used to send a message to another chat connection. It should be used for generic system messages, like accepting or declining a chat connection, and marking someone public or private. To let the other side know the message is generated
from the chat program it is a good idea to make the string resemble something like: "\n&lt;CHAT&gt; %s has refused your
connection because your name is too long.\n" 

Receiver: 

Just print the message string.

&lt;CHAT_VERSION&gt;&lt;version string&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

This is used to send your mud client's name and version.

&lt;CHAT_FILE_START&gt;&lt;filename,length&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

This is sent to start sending a chat connection a file. The filename should be just the filename and not a path. Length is
the size of the file inbytes. 

Receiver: 

First should check to make sure you are allowing files from this connection. Make sure the filename is valid and that the
length was trasnmitted. If for any reason the data isn't valid or you don't want to accept files from this person a
CHAT_FILE_DENY should be sent back to abort the transfer. If you want to continue with the transfer you need to start it
off by requesting a block of data with CHAT_FILE_BLOCK_REQUEST.

&lt;CHAT_FILE_DENY&gt;&lt;message&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

This is used when a CHAT_FILE_START has been received and you want to prevent the transfer from continuing. &lt;message&gt; is a
string telling the reason it was denied. For example, if the file already existed you might deny it with: "File already
exists." 

Receiver: 

Print the deny message. Deal with cleaning up any files you opened when you tried to start the transfer.

&lt;CHAT_FILE_BLOCK_REQUEST&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

Sent to request the next block of data in a transfer. 

Receiver: 

Need to create a file block to be sent back. File blocks are fixed length so you must not add the CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND byte.
If the end of file is reached need to send a CHAT_FILE_END close up the files and let the user know it is done sending.

&lt;CHAT_FILE_BLOCK&gt;&lt;block of data&gt;

A file block is 500 bytes. A file block is ALWAYS 500 bytes so no CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND should be added.

Receiver: 

The receiver needs to keep track of the number of bytes written to properly write the last block of data. If you keep track
of the bytes written you know when to expect that last block that probably doesn't have a full 500 bytes to be saved. File
transfers are receiver driven, so for each block of data you accept, you need to send another CHAT_FILE_BLOCK_REQUEST back
out to get more data.

&lt;CHAT_FILE_END&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

Close up your files and be done with it. This command isn't required for TinTin since it keeps track of the file transfer
progress itself.

&lt;CHAT_FILE_CANCEL&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

Either side can send this command to abort a file transfer in progress.

&lt;CHAT_PING_REQUEST&gt;&lt;timing data&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

The timing data is up to the ping requester. TinTin sends a 64 bit time stamp.

&lt;CHAT_PING_RESPONSE&gt;&lt;timing data&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

When receiving a CHAT_PING_REQUEST you should send back the timing data.

&lt;CHAT_PEEK_CONNECTIONS&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

The sender requests connections from another connection asking to see all the people that person has marked as public. The
receiver needs to put all the ip addresses, port numbers, and names in a tilda delimited string and send them back as a
peek list.

&lt;CHAT_PEEK_LIST&gt;&lt;address&gt;~&lt;port&gt;~&lt;name&gt;~&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

The receiver needs to put all the ip addresses, port numbers, and names in a tilda delimited string and send them back as a
peek list.

&lt;CHAT_SNOOP_START&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

The sender requests to start or stop snooping data from a chat connection. The Receiver decides whether to allow snooping
or not.

&lt;CHAT_SNOOP_DATA&gt;&lt;message&gt;&lt;CHAT_END_OF_COMMAND&gt;

Send by a mud client in snoop or forward mode. The message should be echoed by the receiver, but not be further forwarded
to avoid infinite loops.
</Description>
</Help>