<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Help>
  <Command Name="Chat" />
  <Syntax>{command} {argument}</Syntax>
  <Description>
    The #chat command is used to create peer to peer connections to other mud clients, 
    typically for the purpose of chatting and sending files.
    
    This is a decentralized chat system, meaning you have to exchange ip addresses and
    port numbers with other users in order to connect to them.
  </Description>
  <Example Usage="#chat {initialize} {port}">
    Launches a private chat server.
    The port number is optional.   (default 4050)

    People can connect to your chat server instance by specifying your ip address and port number.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {name} {your name}">
    By default, your name is set to TinTin.  However, most servers will reject you if there is already someone with that name already connected.
    That chat name can include color codes.
    Some names aren't accepted by tt++ chat servers, like the name 'all', and names longer than 20 characters.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {call} {ip address} {port}">
    Is used to connect to another chat server.
    The port number is optional.   (default 4050)
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {color} {color names}">
    The default chat color is bold red\.
    This can be changed with the '#chat color' command.
    
    Example: #chat color bold yellow
    Example using a 256 color code:  #chat color &lt;cde&gt;
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {message} {user|all} {text}">
    This is the main command used for communication.
    If you use '#chat message all', the message is marked as public and send to everyone you are connected to.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {emote} {user|all} {text}">
    This command works exactly like #chat message, except in appearance as all it does is prepend your name to the message.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {paste} {user|all} {text}">
    This command allows pasting, appending input that is followed in quick succession to the message.
    Keep in mind that most mud clients won't properly receive messages that are longer than 40 lines.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {reply} {text}">
    Replies to the last person you received a private message from.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {send} {user|all}">
    Sends a raw data string to another person and subsequently requires knowledge of the Mud Master Chat Protocol (MMCP) in order to use it.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat dnd">
    DND stands for 'do not disturb' and toggles your DND state.
    When enabled, all new incoming connections are automatically closed.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {ip} {address}">
    Sets your ip address, which isn't set by default, and is sent when connecting to another mud client.
    TinTin# ignores the reported ip of other MUD clients and grabs the socket address.
    Other MUD clients might need it set.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {who}">
    Shows all people you are connected to.
    The first column shows a reference number for the connection, which can be used instead of the connection's name when sending someone a message.
    The second column shows the connection's name.
    The third column shows flags set for the connection, (P)rivate, (I)gnore, (S)erve, (F)orward to user, and (f)orward from user.
    The following columns show ip, port, and MUD client name.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {info}">
    Shows your name, ip address, port, download dir, reply, and DND status.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {ignore} {user}">
    Ignores the specified user, who won't be notified that you're ignoring them.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {private} {user|all}">
    Disables the peek and request command for the given connection.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {public} {user|all}">
    Is the opposite of the private command.
    Allows the peek and request command to work for a given connection.
    New connections are public by default.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {peek} {user}">
    Shows the given user's public connections.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {request} {user}">
    Obtains the specified user's public connections and automatically connect to them, if not already.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {ping} {user}">
    Displays the ping request time round-trip, in milli seconds.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {zap} {user|all}">
    Closes the connection to the specified user or all users.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {forward} {user}">
    Forwards all chat messages to the specified user as snoop data.
    To avoid infinite loops, forwarding to a user is disabled when receiving snoop data from that user.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {forwardall} {user}">
    Forwards everything that is saved in the scrollback buffer to the specified user as snoop data.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {serve} {user}">
    Forwards all public chat messages to the specified user plus all public chat messages from that user to everyone you are connected to.
    To avoid infinite loops the messages are forwarded as private messages.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {group} {user} {name}">
    Assigns the specified user to a group.
    You can use a group name with the emote, message, and send commands.
    If you use '#chat group' without an argument, it will behave like '#chat who', showing a list of all users and their group name.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {sendfile} {user} {filename}">
    Sends a file to the given user.
    They must accept it before transfer begins.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {accept} {user}">
    Accepts a file transfer after the user has offered to send a file.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {decline} {user}">
    Declines a file transfer after the user has offered to send a file.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {cancel} {user}">
    Cancels a file transfer after it has been started.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {filestat} {user}">
    Shows information about a file transfer currently in progress.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#chat {downloaddir} {directory}">
    Sets the directory path location where new downloads are to be placed.
  </Example>
</Help>