<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Help>
  <Command Name="List" />
  <Syntax>{&lt;variable&gt;} {&lt;option&gt;} {&lt;arguments&gt;}</Syntax>
  <Description>
    Lists are container collections that handle collisions and are highly scaleable.
    Indexing is similar to a HashTable.

    Collections contain an index a value between 0 and the collection's length-1; where length is greater than 0.
    Indexes may also contain the 'key' for lookup; where key is a string literal.
  </Description>
  <Example Usage="$var[1], $var[2], $var[-1]">
    Display items in a list by using its index.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#foreach command use $&lt;list&gt;[%*]">
    Loop through all items in a collection.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {add} {&lt;argument1&gt;} {&lt;argument2&gt;} {...}">
    Adds an item to the given list for each argument provided.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {clear}">
    Empties the specified 'list' variable.
    Equivalent:  #variable {&lt;variable&gt;} {}
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {create} {&lt;argument1&gt;} {&lt;argument2&gt;} {...}">
    Clears the given list and adds an item for each additional argument provided.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {delete} {&lt;index&gt;} {[number=1]}">
    Removes the item at the specified index.
    The 'number' argument is the number of items to delete.
    If omitted, 1 is used by default.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {find} {&lt;argument&gt;} {&lt;variable&gt;}">
    Allows searching for an item that matches the provided argument.
    If no match is found, the destination variable is set to 0.
    Otherwise, the variable is set to contain the index of the matched item.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {get} {&lt;indext&gt;} {&lt;variable&gt;}">
    Retrieves the list's item at the specified index.
    If the index doesn't exist, the destination variable is set to 0.
    Otherwise, the destination variable is set to contain the value of the found index.
    
    Alternatively you can use '$list[&lt;index&gt;&gt;]' to retrieve the value using the interface for associative arrays.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {insert} {&lt;index&gt;} {&lt;argument&gt;}">
    Inserts the item at the specified index.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {set} {&lt;index&gt;} {&lt;argument&gt;}">
    Changes the value of the provided index to the specified argument.
    
    Alternatively you can use: '#variable {&lt;list&gt;[&lt;index&gt;]} {&lt;argument&gt;}'
    to change the value using the interface for associative arrays.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {size} {&lt;variable&gt;}">
    Retrieves the number of items in the collection and stores it in the specified destination variable.
    
    Alternatively you can use:  '&amp;list[]' to retrieve the number of items in the collection using the interface for associative arrays.
  </Example>
  <Example Usage="#list {&lt;list&gt;} {sort} {&lt;argument&gt;}">
    Inserts the specified argument in alphabetical/numerical order.
  </Example>
</Help>