<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Help>
  <Command Name="Map" />
  <Syntax></Syntax>
  <Description>
    Used for the auto mapper and supports most of the auto mapping functionality available.
    For basic path tracking see path.

    To start mapping use #map create &lt;number of rooms&gt; which will create the first room and set the maximum number of rooms to
    the specified amount. If you don't specify a number of rooms it'll default to 15,000 rooms. To enter the map use:
    #map goto 1 which will move you to the first room.

    In order to add rooms you can simply move around. The default directions, n ne e se s sw w nw u d, are created by default.
    If your mud has non standard directions you must add these with the pathdir command for them to work.

    There are three ways to display the map. The first is #map map which will display an ascii map of the surrounding rooms.
    The second option is splitting the screen in 3 sections, using #split 10 1 where 10 is the size of the top section.
    With #map flag vtmap the map will be shown in the top section, and will be updated as you move around. The third option is to
    create a MAP ENTER ROOM event and have it execute: #map map 80x24 map.txt. This will write a printout of the map to the file
    map.txt and if you use: tail -fs 0.1 map.txt in another terminal it'll continously update your map in that terminal window.

    Quite a few muds have overlapping areas or even overlapping rooms within areas. To deal with this you can stretch out rooms
    by turning a room into a link between 2 other rooms. You do this with #map roomflag void. Keep in mind a room with this flag
    should only have 2 exits. You can easily insert void rooms using: #map insert &lt;direction&gt; void.

    Like most auto mappers you can speedwalk easily. Assuming you named the first room recall using #map name recall while
    standing in the first room, next walked from Midgaard to Bubba in the Mushroom Forest whose room you named Bubba's bar, you
    can speedwalk back using: #map run recall. Of course it's faster to simply recall back, in which case you can tell the mapper
    you are back in midgaard using: #map goto recall.

    If you particularly enjoy watching the map update itself with vtmap enabled, or are anxious to try this out, you can slow
    walk back to Bubba. Enter #map run {Bubba's bar} 0.75 to do this.

    After all this hard work you can save your map using #map write &lt;filename&gt; which can be loaded back in with #map read
    &lt;filename&gt;. To go back to the room you were in when you saved the map use after loading it: #map return.

    For more information about the available commands use '#help map' within tintin which has the most up to date command summary.
  </Description>
</Help>