<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Help>
  <Command Name="List" Modified="9/16/2017" />
  <Syntax>{&lt;variable&gt;} {&lt;option&gt;} {&lt;arguments&gt;}</Syntax>
  <Description>
Lists in TinTin# are associative arrays with a numeric index. The list command makes it easier to emulate array behavior by
automatically renumbering items whenever one is removed or inserted.

When the list command requires an index a value between 1 and the list's length should be provided. A negative value can be
given as well, in which case -1 equals the last item in the list, -2 the second last, etc.

You can directly display items in a list by using the index, for example: $var[1], $var[2], $var[-1], etc.

To loop through all items in a list using the foreach command use $&lt;list&gt;[%*].

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {add} {&lt;argument1&gt;} {&lt;argument2&gt;} {...}

#list add will add an item to the given list for each argument provided.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {clear}

#list clear will empty the given list variable. The command is equivalent to: #variable {&lt;variable&gt;} {}

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {create} {&lt;argument1&gt;} {&lt;argument2&gt;} {...}

#list create will clear the given list and will add an item for each additional argument provided.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {delete} {&lt;index&gt;} {[number]

#list delete will remove the item at the given index. The number argument is the number of items to delete, if omitted 1
item will be deleted.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {find} {&lt;argument&gt;} {&lt;variable&gt;}

#list find allows searching for an item that matches the provided argument. If no match is found the destination variable
is set to 0, otherwise the variable is set to contain the index of the matched item.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {get} {&lt;indext&gt;} {&lt;variable&gt;}

#list get will retrieve the list's item at the provided index. If the index doesn't exist the destination variable is set
to 0, otherwise the destination variable is set to contain the value of the found index. Alternatively you can use
$list[&lt;index&gt;&gt;] to retrieve the value using the interface for associative arrays.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {insert} {&lt;index&gt;} {&lt;argument&gt;}

#list insert will insert the item at the given index. If the index is a positive number the item is created at the given
index. If the index is a negative number the item is created at the next index. Hence using -1 will append a new item to
the end of the list, and using 1 will prepend a new item to the beginning of the list.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {set} {&lt;index&gt;} {&lt;argument&gt;}

#list set will change the value of the provided index to the given argument. Alternatively you can use:
#variable {&lt;list&gt;[&lt;index&gt;]} {&lt;argument&gt;} to change the value using the interface for associative arrays.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {size} {&lt;variable&gt;}

#list size will retrieve the number of items in the list and store it in the provided destination variable. Alternatively,
you can use: &amp;list[] to retrieve the number of items in a list using the interface for associative arrays.

#list {&lt;list&gt;} {sort} {&lt;argument&gt;}

#list sort will insert the provided argument in alphabetical order.
</Description>
</Help>